我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R Labs,
我秘密打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界
but in doing so,
也因此出现了新的威胁
I opened up our world to new threats.
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The flash"...
我刺中了你母亲的心脏
I stabbed your mother in the heart
之后我终于释怀了
and I was free.
艾迪是他的先人
Eddie is his ancestor.
如果艾迪死了  他就不会出生
If eddie dies, he'll never be born.
他的存在正在被抹除
He's being erased from existence.
-吉迪恩  -在  斯旺教授
- Gideon? - Yes, Professor Thawne?
我在哪里
Where the hell am I?
我被米德韦城市大学的
I was accepted Into the forensic science program
米德韦城市大学
鉴证科学系
鉴证科录取了
at midway city university.
我要离开中城
I'm leaving Central City.
乔  你有个儿子
Joe, you have a son.
你好  我是沃利  弗朗辛的儿子
Hi, I'm Wally. I'm Francine's son.
这些赛事
These races?
我只有这样才能付得起我妈的医疗费
That's the only way that I can pay for my mom's hospital bills.
杰西是我的女儿  极速抓走了她
Jesse's my daughter and Zoom has her.
爸爸  快救我
Daddy? Please help me.
不要让他把我关回去
Don't let him take me back there.
我会不惜一切也要把你救回来
I would do anything to get you back.
有很多原因会让我们选择逃避
There are many reasons why we run,
但通常是想要逃避所面临的问题
but usually it's to avoid what's right in front of us--
需要做的决定
a decision to be made
或者正身处的窘境
or a dilemma we have to face.
最近  我所做的一切都是在逃避
Lately, for me, it feels like running is all I've been doing.
现在什么情况  西斯科
What you got for me, Cisco?
你已经当了一早上雷锋了
You've been playing good Samaritan all morning.
歇歇吧
Take a break.
你确定你不想去中城警局关心下帕蒂吗
Are you sure you don't want to get to CCPD, give Patty your attention?
不用  我可以晚会儿见她
No, I can see her later.
我们不能再浪费时间了
'Cause we cannot afford to waste any more time.
怎么  自从你来之后我们难道都在喝小酒吗
What, ' cause we've just been sipping mai tais since you got here?
我不知道我来了之后你在干什么
I don't know what you been sipping since I got here,
但是巴里必须变得更好  更强  更快
but Barry needs to get better, stronger, faster.
我们要让他做好面对极速的准备
We need to train to prepare for Zoom.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
你今天早上还没喝咖啡
You haven't had your coffee this morning.
我早上喝咖啡了  别用吸的
I had my coffee this morning. Don't slurp.
别  别
Don't. Don't.
别
Don't.
凯斯特街上一辆失控的化学品运输车正向南行驶
Runaway chemical transport truck heading south on Kester.
这就去
On it.
我没办法停下卡车
Hey, I can't stop the truck!
有人动了手脚
Somebody rigged it!
抱歉
Sorry!
千万不能撞车
You can't let that truck crash.
否则整个城区都会遭殃
If you do, you'll take out a whole city block.
真棒  谢谢你
Great. Thank you.
真是谢谢你了
Thank you for that.
好险  好险
That was close, that was close.
剧情发展不妙啊
Oh, and the plot thickens.
前面是死路
Uh, dead-end up ahead.
你得赶紧走
You got to get out of there!
不是吧
Oh, come on.
太好了
Yes!
刚才真是太惊险了
That one was a little close.
赞  现在  求你了
Nice! Now can you please,
求求你休息一下吧
please take a break?
-刚才那个训练怎么样  -不错
- How's that for training? - Great.
听着  我们会抓到极速的
Look, we're gonna catch Zoom.
我们已经把乌龟人关起来了
We got Turtle locked up in the pipeline.
现在要做的就是想个办法偷走极速的速度
All we got to do is use him to figure out how to steal
然后我们把你的女儿救回来
Zoom's speed and then we'll get your daughter back.
时间估计比我们想像的要长
That might take longer than we thought.
为什么
Why's that?
因为乌龟人死了
Because Turtle's dead.
巴里  你得赶快回来
Barry, we need you back here stat.
好的  现在就走
All right. I'm on my way.
吉迪恩
Gideon.
刚才的计划成功了吗  斯旺博士
Was the trip a success, professor Thawne?
是的  我终于知道
I believe it was. I've finally figured out
闪电侠来自哪个时间段了
what time period the Flash is from.
现在让我们想想该怎么回家
Now let's figure out a way to get home.
他最好别玩假死的把戏
He better not be pulling a Juliet.
没错  我也看戏剧的
Yeah, that's right. I see plays.
-他死了  西斯科  -这是怎么回事
- He's dead, Cisco. - How'd this happen?
初步脑部扫瞄发现了急性脑动脉瘤
Preliminary brain scan shows an acute brain aneurysm.
就在我们抓住他那一晚  还真是巧
The night we captured him. How's that for timing?
你什么意思
What does that mean?
你觉得是我干的吗  加里克
You think I did this, Garrick?
这个人是我们阻止极速的关键
This man is the key to us stopping Zoom,
是救出我女儿的关键
the key to me saving my daughter.
我怎么会对他下手
Why would I want that?
你所做的一切我都不理解  哈里森
Never understood why you do anything, Harrison.
你理解不理解无所谓  加里克
That's fine with me, Garrick.
大伙们  行了
Guys, look.
我们得想出阻止极速的办法
We need to figure out how to stop zoom.
我们目前所尝试的都失败了
Everything we've tried so far has failed.
我们得想点新东西
We need to start thinking outside the box.
我们现在都还不知道怎么关闭那些缺口
I mean, we haven't even figured out how to close the breaches yet.
或许我们该从那里开始
Maybe that's where we should start.
好主意
That's a good idea.
-我来  -我帮你
- I'll get on that. - I'll help.
我得去中城警局了
I've got to get to the CCPD.
各位稍后再见
I'll check in with you guys later.
好
Okay.
每当你感到威尔斯和你们站在一边时
Every time you think that Wells is on your team,
都会出些事让你感到怀疑
something happens that makes you doubt it.
中城警局
我想知道你能不能帮我检验一下这个痕迹
Hey, I just wanted to see if you could run this trace for me.
今早有人把它和运输酒精的汽车混一起了
Someone messed with an ethanol transport truck this morning.
他们找到了刹车轨迹  却和齿轮轴搞混了
They cut the brake line and tampered with the gear shafts.
好  没问题
Okay, yeah.
好
Okay.
堆了这么多文件啊
Wow. Backed up, huh?
是啊
I am, yeah.
我想等我从鉴证科毕业了
Yeah, I guess I'll find out what that's like
就会明白那是什么感觉了
once I finish CSI school.
是啊  会明白的
Yeah, you will.
我想会的
I guess.
听着  巴里  我知道你很难过
Look, Barry, I know that you're upset,
可我不想看到我们的关系变成这样
but I was hoping it wouldn't be like this between us.
你觉得我们的关系会是什么样
What did you think it was gonna be like?
我只想走之前我们至少能说说话
I ju--I just thought we could at least talk before I left.
你要走了  我不知道
You're moving. I don't know.
我是说  只是感觉现在
I mean, it just doesn't feel like there's much
没什么好说的  对吗
to talk about now, right?
我想没有
I guess not.
我听到你们聊的了
I sort of overheard some of that.
帕蒂要去米德韦城市大学念鉴证科
Patty's going to CSI school in Midway City.
她两天后就走
She's moving in two days.
我是说  你可以挽留她的
I mean, you don't have to let her leave.
成为鉴证专员是她毕生的梦想
She's wanted to be a CSI her whole life.
我不想成为绊脚石
I'm not gonna stand in the way of that.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我去见了弗朗辛
Just went to see Francine and, uh...
她时日不多了
she doesn't have much time.
我已经和她道过别了  要是...
I already said my good-byes, if--
要是你想也可以去一趟
if you want to do the same.
没有用
It's not gonna work.
关闭缺口就像解决爱因斯坦的谜语
Closing the breaches, that's like solving Einstein's riddle.
我十岁的时候就解开爱因斯坦的谜语了
I solved Einstein's riddle when I was ten.
是吗  那可能地球二的爱因斯坦
Yeah, well, maybe Earth-2 Einstein
没我们这里的聪明
wasn't as clever as ours.
你知道那可是我的地球二  对吧
You realize this Earth is my Earth-2, right?
听着
Listen to this.
要是我们知道如何控制我的超能力
What if we can figure out how to control my powers?
那我们就能找到极速  抢在他前面
We could find Zoom, get the jump on him.
主意不错  那你去研究吧
That's a good idea. You should get on that.
我需要你帮忙  哈里
I need your help, Harry.
你所需要的  拉蒙
What you need, Ramon,
就是搞清楚什么能触发你的震波
is to figure out what triggers your vibes.
没错  我不知道什么能触发震波
Exactly, and I don't know what triggers them.
完全毫无联系  有时是当我
It's completely inconsistent. Sometimes it's when I touch
触碰到和缺口有关的东西
something that belongs to a breacher,
有时就这么发生了
sometimes it just happens.
事出必有因  原因  结果
There's always a cause. Cause, effect.
不用爱因斯坦也能弄清楚
Doesn't take Einstein to figure that out.
好  那么原因是什么
Okay, so what is the cause?
你看见我想用震波感应光博士了
You saw when I tried to vibe Dr. Light,
我用震波感应你费了好一会儿
when I tried to vibe you, took a while to work.
对
Yes.
对  没错
Yes, it did.
去时间穹顶找我
Meet me in the time vault.
为什么
For what?
有人吗
Hello?
哈里
Harry?
好吧  他这是要我在
Of course, now he's gonna make me wait
这□人的盲文小屋里等着了
in this freaky-ass Braille room.
你好  西斯科
Hi, Cisco.
停  别那样
Stop! Don't do that!
我找到了你的开关
I figured out your trigger.
肾上腺素喷张
A rush of adrenaline.
多巴胺冲击大脑
Dopamine floods the brain.
而触发震波最快的方式就是
And the quickest way to achieve that result...
恐惧
fear!
别动
Do not move!
不可能
You can't be.
水星实验室
你看见了什么
What did you see?
逆闪电
The Reverse-Flash.
他来了
He's here.
水星实验室
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
克里斯蒂娜·麦吉
Christina Mcgee.
你是谁
Who are you?
你得跟我走
You're coming with me.
闪电侠
Flash.
艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eobard Thawne.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am?
你已经死了
You died!
水星   实验
谢谢你告诉我
Good to know.
猜怎么着  闪电侠
And guess what, Flash.
我知道你来自哪个时间段
I know what time period you're from.
也就意味着很快
So that means very soon...
你就会死
you will die.
不
No.
你没事吧  小巴
You okay, Bar?
我没事  就是信息量有点大
I'm good, yeah. It's just a lot.
艾迪·斯旺死了  那艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eddie Thawne died, so Eobard Thawne
就不该存在啊  对吗
should have been erased out of existence, right?
不一定
Not necessarily.
有可能艾尔伯德待在神速力里
It's possible Eobard was in the speed force,
那正好保护了他
protecting him like a bomb shelter,
保住了他的命和时间线的完整
keeping him alive and his time line intact.
这种现象叫"时间线残余"
It's what's known as a "time line remnant"
什么东西
A what now?
这里  让我演示给你看
Here, let me...show you.
这个
This?
这个  是现在
This...is now.
也就是今天
Here, today.
这是斯旺来的时间点
This is the time Thawne comes from.
这个是你们将他从现实中抹去的时刻
This is the moment you all erased him from existence,
可因为斯旺来自未来
But since Thawne is from the future,
这便是他时间线的起始点
this is where his time line begins.
这就是为什么他还活着
That's why he's still alive.
这个斯旺还没有穿越回去
This Thawne has not yet traveled back in time
杀掉巴里的母亲
to kill Barry's mother.
他是第一次出现在这个时间段
He's here now in this time period for the first time.
"时间线残余"
"Time line remnant."
解释了为什么没有任何变化
Explains why nothing's changed.
是的  也解释了为什么他不知道我名字
Yeah, it also explains why he didn't know my name
也不记得我们之前见过
or that we have met before.
对他来说  没见过  那是未来的事
To him, you hadn't. Not until the future.
如果斯旺在第二次穿越时间之前死了
If Thawne dies before he can time travel again,
那样救得了巴里的母亲吗
will that save Barry's mother?
不行  不是那样的
No. That's not how it works.
在我们的时间线上  巴里的母亲已经死了
In our time line, Barry's mother is already dead,
她的死已固定在时间线上了
and her death is a fixed point.
无法修改
Nothing can change that.
好吧  我会了结这一切
All right, well, I'm gonna end this,
在这条时间线里彻底解决他
him, in this time once and for all.
咱们先去找麦吉博士  然后再想
Let's find Dr. Mcgee, then we'll figure out
怎么对付斯旺  好吗
what to do about Thawne, okay?
我要去看看爱瑞丝
I got to go check on Iris.
拉蒙
Ramon.
凯瑟琳  我知道你担心麦吉博士
Caitlin, I know you're worried about Dr. Mcgee,
但我们会救回她的
but we're gonna get her back.
不是那事  是杰伊
It's not that. It's Jay.
杰伊怎么了
What about Jay?
他病了  而且情况越来越糟
He's sick, and it's getting worse.
当极速偷走了他的速度
When Zoom stole his speed,
他的细胞受到了影响
it affected him on a cellular level.
我们必须做点什么
We need to do something about it.
好吧  做什么
All right, like what?
我想我们应该用和他本身细胞无异
I think we should replace his dying cells
且健康的细胞替换病死细胞
with healthy ones indistinguishable from his.
那我们要怎么做
How do we do that?
找到他地球一的二重身
We find his Earth-1 doppelganger.
水星实验室
那里
There.
超光速粒子
Tachyons?
去年一个穿黄衣服的人
A man in a yellow suit tried to steal
也想偷另一台超光速粒子原型
another tachyon prototype last year.
我之前也一定被困在了这里
I must have gotten stuck here once before
也无法获取足够的神速力
and not been able to access enough of the speed force.
超光速粒子应该够了
Tachyons should do it.
我要你隔离并加速
I want you to isolate and accelerate
它其中的活性粒子
their energetic properties for me.
我不知道能不能做到
I don't know if I can do that.
如果你还想活命
If you want to stay alive...
那就学吧
learn.
凡妮
Franny.
你今天感觉如何
How you feeling today?
好多了
Better now.
我让你俩单独聊好了
I'm gonna let you two talk, okay?
好的
Okay.
需要我给你带些什么吗
Can I get you anything?
带你弟弟来就行了
Oh, just that brother of yours
这会是我们一家人第一次大团圆
so all of us can be together for the first time.
是啊  他应该来的
Yeah, he should be here.
他的母亲要离开他了
His mother is leaving him.
不能因此怪他闹脾气
Can't blame him for being angry about that.
我只希望趁我还能帮上忙
I just wish he'd get all that anger out
他能发泄出那些怒火
while I'm here to help.
对你也是一样  爱瑞丝
Same thing goes for you, Iris.
临死时你会明白一件事
One thing you learn when you're dying
那就是别再隐藏
is not to hold anything back.
你有什么想对我说的吗
You want to say something to me?
想说就要抓紧了
You need to say it while you can.
我成长的过程中有很多美好的回忆
I have so many great memories from when I grew up.
现在当我回想起它们的时候
Now when I think about those memories,
我只好奇一件事
I can only wonder what it would have been like
如果你和沃利在的话  会是怎样
if you and Wally would have been there.
我不再因为已经发生的事
I'm not angry at you anymore
生你的气了
for what happened.
我只是希望你能再早一点回到我们身边
I just wish you would have come back to us a lot sooner.
因为那时我也会原谅你
Because I would have forgiven you then...
就像我现在原谅你一样
just like I'm forgiving you now.
对不起
I'm sorry.
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
我不知道为什么会这么难过
I don't know why this is so hard.
我几乎不怎么了解她
I barely even know her.
尖端科研实验室的面部识别软件
The facial recognition software at S.T.A.R. Labs
也没有任何发现
didn't find anything either.
不  但还是有更多数据库要看
No, but there's still more databases to check.
我们会找到他的二重身的
We'll find his doppelganger.
-谢谢你  巴里  -没事
- Thanks, Barry. - Yeah.
你好  凯特琳
Hey. Hi, Caitlin.
你好
Hi.
能聊聊吗
Uh, can we... talk?
当然
Uh, yeah, yeah, for sure.
有发现了我会告诉你的
Um, I'll let you know what I find.
-谢谢  -没事
- Thanks. - Yeah.
有什么事
What's up?
我都不知道你和尖端科研实验室有合作
I didn't know you were working with S.T.A.R. labs.
是啊
Yeah, um, uh, yeah.
我和乔时不时帮帮忙
Joe and I help out every once in a while.
真的吗
Really?
真的  也许我不该告诉你
Yeah, I probably shouldn't tell you this,
但是那里发生了很多奇怪的事
but there's a lot of weird stuff that happens over there.
你来就是要和我说这事吗
Is that what you came to tell me?
你一直避而不谈我要离开的事
You're just rolling with the whole "me leaving" thing.
我不知道该和你说什么  帕蒂
Yeah, well, I don't know what to tell you, Patty.
我爱的每一个人在某个时刻都会离我而去
Everyone in my life that I love leaves at some point.
我已经习惯了
Kind of getting used to it.
你从未告诉过我你爱我
You... never told me you loved me.
看来现在也没机会了
Yeah, I guess I don't get that chance now.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你到底是怎么了
What is it? What's going on with you?
你为什么要这样
Why are you being like this?
我的生活很复杂  我不想你
My life is complicated, and I don't want you
有遗憾  好吗
to have regrets, all right?
我不想你错过
I don't want you to miss out
你一直想做的事
on something that you've always wanted to do.
但愿我们俩的事情
And I wish that things were different
能有所不同
for both of us.
但事与愿违
You know, but they're not.
对不起
Sorry.
一样
Me too.
你对我的护目镜做了什么
So what did you do to my goggles?
我增加了一个波长触发器
I added a wavelength trigger
来刺激你大脑的恐惧神经末梢
to stimulate the fear receptors in your brain.
然后撤掉已有的能触发慢波睡眠的功能
Then I took what you already had to induce slow-wave sleep,
把它升级至四级睡眠
upgraded it to get you to stage-four sleep.
不  这样很好
No, this is good.
-这样更利于我们控制  -好吧
- This will give us more control. - Okay.
现在我就能知道你的震波时长
Now I'll be able to dictate how long you vibe for.
戴上试试
Put 'em on.
我会看到什么
What am I gonna see?
不知道  从未试过
I don't know. Never done this before.
告诉我你看到的  好引你去该去的地方
You'll have to tell me so I can steer you where you need to be.
拉蒙  你想找到逆闪电
Ramon, you want to find Reverse-Flash,
那就戴上护目镜
put on the goggles.
好
Okay.
好的
Attaboy.
戴吧
Go ahead.
好爽
Oh-ho-ho, yeah, man.
现在震波全面开启
I'm in full-on vibe mode right now.
-你看到了什么  -很难说
- What do you see? - It's hard to explain.
不同的事件
It's different events.
不同时间的不同事件
Different events in time.
把注意力集中在逆闪电上
Concentrate on the Reverse-Flash.
好
Okay.
我看到他了
I see him.
靠近他
Move toward him.
好  现在呢
Okay, now what?
想像他和克里斯蒂娜·麦吉在一起
Try to picture him with Christina McGee.
我到底在哪里
Where the hell am I?
充电完毕
It's charged.
你可以走了
You can go now.
你说过会放我走的
You said you'd release me.
是的  我说过  不是吗
Yes, I did. Didn't I?
不
No!
看到了什么
Well, what is it?
她死了
She's dead.
麦吉博士死了
Dr. Mcgee is dead?
我和哈里想完善我的超能力以便找到极速
Harry and I were trying to hone my powers to find Zoom,
结果我们却用超能力找到了逆闪电
and then we ended up using them, finding the Reverse-Flash,
我就是那个时候看到他杀了她
and that's when I saw him kill her.
然后他走了
And then he left.
他走了  他走了是什么意思
He left? What do you mean, he left?
麦吉给他造了一个高速机
McGee built him some kind of speed machine
他进去了  回到了未来
and he ran into and got flung back to the future.
需要超光速能量才能穿越时间
You'd need superluminal energy to send someone through time.
-你是说像超光子  -超光子
- You mean like tachyons? - Tachyons.
一旦激活  我们就能追踪到他们的下落
We can track their location once they've been activated.
-有什么发现吗  -什么也没有
- Anything? - Nothing.
西斯科  你真的看到了吗
Cisco, you're sure that's what you saw?
-很肯定  -好
- I'm positive. - All right.
你还看到了什么
What else did you see?
那里到处都是奇怪的机器
There was all sorts of weird tech everywhere.
有个钟
There was a clock.
钟上显示几点
What time did the clock say?
九点五十二分吧
9:52, I think.
时间和这事有关系吗
How-- how is that relevant?
现在才六点
6:00 now.
你是说我能看到未来吗
Are you telling me I can see the future?
没错
That's exactly what I'm telling you.
得赶紧给这副护目镜取个名了
Those goggles are getting named immediately.
那就是说麦吉博士还活着
But that means Dr. McGee is alive.
-没错  -那好
- That's right. - Yeah, okay.
我们还有3小时52分钟的时间找到她
We have 3 hours, 52 minutes to find her
并阻止逆闪电
and stop Reverse-Flash.
行动吧
Let's do it.
-斯皮沃特  -你好
- Spivot. - Hey.
你一直在看案子的文档
Can't get away from those case files, huh?
只是有灵感翻一翻
Oh, just following up on a hunch.
你会怀念出外勤的日子的
You're gonna miss the action, right?
也许会有一点吧
Maybe. A little.
-我会想念你的  -我也会想你
- I'm gonna miss you. - Miss you too.
知道有人会想我还是挺开心的
It's nice to know someone will.
等等  这是在说巴里吗
Wait, we talking about Barry?
感觉我们说的是巴里
'cause it sounds like we're talking about Barry.
他一直跟我说  有些事情
He kept telling me there was stuff
不能让我知道
he couldn't share with me,
然而我为了查清到底是什么事
and I've been going a little crazy
已经快要疯掉了
trying to figure out what that stuff is.
是啊  巴里总是把事情藏在心里
Yeah, Barry's not great at sharing.
-你也是这样  -这是什么意思
- Neither are you. - What do you mean?
巴里刚才告诉我
Barry just told me that, you know,
他有时会帮你处理尖端科研实验室的事情
sometimes he helps you out with S.T.A.R. Labs stuff.
没错  他有空就会帮我
Yeah, he does when he has a few extra minutes.
我之前并不知道
I didn't know that.
我是说  我都在这工作这么久了
I mean, the whole time I've been working here
你从未说过这事
you never mentioned it to me,
但后来我知道原因了
but then I realized why.
我回顾了巴里之前的一些案子
I went through some of Barry's old cases.
这些案子都跟闪电侠挽救中城有关
All of them involved The Flash saving the day
而其中的一些细节
with details that
是巴里根本不可能知道的
Barry couldn't have possibly even known.
这很奇怪
That's weird.
是啊  的确很奇怪
Yeah, it-- it is weird.
但唯一能讲得通的
The only thing that does make sense
就是巴里是闪电侠
is that Barry is The Flash.
你见过巴里跑步的样子吗
Have you ever seen Barry run?
摇摇晃晃跟鸭子走路一样慢
He waddles like a slow-ass duck.
他不可能是闪电侠  帕蒂
There's no way he's The Flash, Patty.
还记得我刚来上班时
You know, when I started this job,
你跟我说工作中要学会撒谎
you told me I had to learn how to lie to do it.
你这谎撒得不怎么样  乔
You're a terrible liar, Joe.
再见
See you.
液氮装备挺棒
Nice nitrous kit.
总有一天你会被抓的
You're gonna get caught one of these days.
你心里很清楚  对吧  会被关进监狱
You know that, right? Get thrown in jail?
等不再需要付医药费了  我就不去比赛了
I'll stop racing when these hospital bills stop coming in.
我今天去看妈妈了
I saw mom today.
她说你有些日子没去看她了
She says you haven't been by in a while.
是的  她知道原因
Yeah, she knows why.
她觉得是因为你在生她的气
She thinks it's because you're angry with her.
我有理由生气
I have every right to be angry.
我活了20年  然后毫无征兆地
Nothing for 20 years, then out of nowhere,
她跟我说  我有个姐姐  还有个爸爸
she tells me I have a sister, I have--I have a father.
是啊  你难道忘了我也有相同的遭遇
Yeah, the same thing happened to me too, remember?
你这样会造成树欲静而风不止
But that shouldn't keep you from seeing her
子欲见而亲不待的遗憾
before you can't anymore.
不是的  不是这样的
No. Look...That's not what it is.
那是怎么回事  沃利
Then what is it, Wally?
我得走了
I got to go.
去年  我的未婚夫死了...
Last year, my fiance died...
走得很突然
unexpectedly.
上一秒他还活着  下一秒就...死了
One moment he was here, the next...gone.
我都没来得及跟他道别
I didn't get a chance to say good-bye to him,
让他知道他对我多么重要
to tell him everything that he meant to me,
让他知道他就是我的全部...
that he was my world...
让他知道我爱他
that he was loved.
我一定要把握跟你妈妈  也就是我妈妈
But today I got to say good-bye to your mom.
道别的机会
My mom.
这能让遭遇了这些家庭变故的你我
And it helped us both find peace
得到内心的平静
with what happened to our family.
沃利  不要犯一个
Wally, don't make a mistake
让你遗憾终生的错误
you're gonna regret the rest of your life.
乘还有机会  去看看妈妈吧
Go see your mom while you still can.
没有发现超光子活动的迹象
No sign of tachyon activity.
我们快没时间了  一定要快点找到
We're running out of time. We've got to find them.
设备激活后  需要几分钟才能达到
It'll take a few minutes for the device to reach full power
全功率运转状态  但在找到它的时候
once it's activated, but when we find it,
你一定要快速到达
you're gonna have to get there fast.
-巴里  -怎么了
- Hey, barry. - Yeah?
有关杰伊的二重身  你还有别的发现吗
Have you found out anything else about Jay's doppelganger?
没有在这个地球找到杰伊·加里克
There's no Jay Garrick on this earth.
这就怪了  每个人都有二重身的
That's so weird. Everyone has a doppelganger.
要不直接问问杰伊
Maybe just ask Jay.
他人不错
He's a good guy.
问问他  我相信他会告诉你的
Just ask him. I'm sure he'll tell you.
好吧
Okay.
等我一下  怎么了
Hold on. What's up?
有麻烦了  帕蒂知道你就是闪电侠了
We got a problem. Patty knows you're The Flash.
-什么  -她打了我个措手不及
- What? - She caught me off guard.
好吧  是我演砸了
I mean, I played it off,
但你要想想  她那么聪明
but come on, she's a smart girl.
总之  她翻看了一些案子的文档
Anyway, she was going through some case files
再加上你那么古怪的行为
and you were acting all squirrely.
这会儿又怪到我头上了
This is my fault now?
-不  不怪任何人  -天啊
- No, it's nobody's fault. - Oh, my god.
-也许你该告诉她  -不行
- Maybe you should tell her. - No.
帕蒂是个值得信赖的人
Patty's trustworthy.
跟这个无关  乔
It's not even about that, Joe.
我不想又让一个人成为极速或逆闪电
I-I don't want another person that Zoom or Reverse-Flash
或其他超能力者可以牵制我的筹码
or any of these meta-humans can use against me.
我不想那样  帕蒂不能因此受到伤害
I don't want it. Patty can't get hurt over this.
发现超光子了  在87街和J大街那里
Tachyons! 87th and Avenue J.
那肯定是水星实验室秘密基地之一
Must be one of Mercury Labs' off-site facilities.
-黑进他们的...  -我已经黑进了他们的安全系统
- Hack into their se-- - I've hacked in the security feed.
-一旦...  -我比你快一步
- And once that-- - I'm one step ahead of you.
快点  巴里
Barry, hurry up!
充电完毕
It's charged.
你可以走了
You can go now.
你说过会放我走的
You said you'd release me.
是的  我说过  不是吗
Yes, I did. Didn't I?
他会杀了她的
He's gonna kill her.
-你还好吗  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
好的  离开这里  好吗  快走
Okay, get out of here, all right? Go! Go!
我靠它才能回家
That was my way home!
你哪儿也别想去
You're not going anywhere.
你还没赢呢  闪电侠
You haven't won here, Flash.
我会另寻他法回去的
I'll find another way back.
你得先过了我这关才行
You're gonna have to get through me first.
你真觉得自己速度快得能阻止我吗
You really think you're fast enough to stop me?
我们走着瞧吧
Let's find out.
有本事就来抓我
Catch me if you can.
比赛开始了
Oh, it's on.
抓住他  巴里
Get him, Bar.
还不够快  斯旺
Not fast enough, Thawne.
我不会再输给你了
I will never lose to you again.
我们之间的纷争  现在就得结束
This war between us, it ends now!
巴里  你得停下
Bar, you got to stop!
巴里  别杀了他  逮住他就好
Bar, don't kill him! Just bring him in!
准备好牢房
Get the cell ready.
他能不能
Hey, he can't...?
穿墙而逃吗  不  他做不到
Phase his way out? No, he can't do that.
这是我们去年关威尔斯博士的牢房
It's the same cell we used to hold Dr. Wells last year.
巴里  你要去哪儿
Barry, where you going?
-我要过去   -不  你不能去
- I'm going down there. - No, you're not.
他越是了解你
The more he learns about you,
你对时间线的改变就越大
the more you will alter the time line.
他杀了我的母亲
He killed my mom!
他来自于未来  他现在还没杀她
He's from the future. He hasn't done that yet.
他还不知道你是闪电侠
He doesn't even know you're the flash,
而且你需要保持现状
and you need to keep it that way.
你说过无论我们怎么做
You already said that his mother's gonna die
他妈妈都会死
no matter what we do.
每次有人扰弄时间线
There's ramifications any time anybody messes
都会出现新的时间分歧
with the time line, and it's impossible to predict
而这些分歧会怎样  是不可预测的
what those ramifications are going to be.
巴里  你抓住了他
Barry, you caught him
你没让他杀了麦吉博士
and you stopped him from killing Dr. Mcgee.
从我的角度来看  这就是赢了
In my book, that's a win.
但感觉并不像是赢了
This doesn't feel like a win.
我得走了
I got to go.
所以  你想和我说什么
So, what'd you want to talk to me about?
我爸爸患有多发性硬化症
My dad had multiple sclerosis.
多年以来  每一天
Every day for years,
我都看着这个如此强壮的男人
I watched This amazingly strong man
为他的生存而奋斗  然后失败
fight for his life...And lose.
所以当另一个我在乎的人为他的生存奋斗时
So, I can't sit by and watch another man I care about
我不能袖手旁观无所作为
fight for his life and not do something about it.
我试着找你的二重身
I tried to find your doppelganger.
同样的DNA  同样的细胞结构
Same DNA, same cellular structure.
我可以用他的活细胞替代你衰竭的细胞
I could replace your dying cells with his living ones.
但是  你在这个地球上没有二重身
But...You don't have a doppelganger on this earth.
凯特琳  这有很好的解释
Caitlin, there is a good explanation.
明天霍福赫公园见  我会带你去看的
Meet me at Hofherr park tomorrow and I'll show you.
你为什么不能直接告诉我呢
Why can't you just tell me?
因为你得亲眼看见才明白
Because you need to see for yourself.
你怎么把衣服弄进戒指里的
How'd you get your suit in your ring?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是西斯科·拉蒙
My name is Cisco Ramon.
我们俩很熟  对吗
And we know each other well, don't we?
我们俩有过一段历史
We have a history together.
你可以这么说
You could say that.
这就是你想知道的吗
And that's all you want to know?
我是怎么把衣服弄进戒指里的
How I got my suit in my ring?
我想让你知道
I want you to know
我就是那个发现你已经回来了的人
that I'm the one who figured out you were back.
我帮忙制止了你
I helped stop you.
是我
Me.
那你是怎么做到的呢
And how'd you do that?
我有超能力
I have powers.
我帮助追查你的行踪然后把你关在这里
And I helped track you down and I put you in here.
你被赋予的能力确实超凡
That's quite the ability you've been given.
而讽刺之处在于
And here's what's so ironic about it.
正是你给了我这些超能力
You gave me these powers.
当你烂在这个你帮我造出的牢房里时
Have fun thinking about that while you rot away in this cell
好好想想这因果吧
that you helped me build.
再见 费利西娅
Bye, Felicia.
中城警局
收到你的短信了
Got your text.
我不确定你想不想见我
I wasn't sure that you would see me,
因为你最近一直躲着我
considering you've been avoiding me lately.
帕蒂  我没有躲着你
Patty, I haven't been avoiding you.
不  只是  忙着
No, just, uh, busy...
你懂的  在中城里极速奔跑
You know, speeding around central city.
我知道你是闪电侠  巴里
I know you're the Flash, Barry.
帕蒂  别这样
Patty, come on.
别再让我觉得自己
Please don't make me feel
比现在的样子更蠢
any more stupid than I already do.
听着  我是警探  我本该知道的
Look, I'm a detective and I should have known.
我只是  我完全被你迷住了
I was just-- I was so smitten with you.
好的  听着  你
Okay, look, what--
你所说的这一切太疯狂了
what you're saying, it's insane.
听着  你不用再和我说谎了  明白吗
Look, you don't have to lie to me anymore, okay?
我懂  我明白你为什么不想告诉我
I understand--I understand why you didn't want to tell me.
我明白为什么你这么疏远
I understand why you've been distant.
听着  所有的事情我都明白
Look, I understand everything.
现在就告诉我实情吧
But just tell me the truth now.
对我说实话
Just be honest with me. Just...
承认你就是闪电侠  我就留下来
admit to me you're the Flash and I'll stay.
我做不到  我不是闪电侠
I can't do that. I'm not him.
太遗憾了  本来留下来挺好的
It's too bad. It would have been nice to stay.
白天与罪恶抗争  晚上跟你在一起
Fight crime during the day and be with you at night.
但我...我想错了
But I was--I was wrong.
保重  巴里
Take care, Barry.
是你吗  闪电侠
Is that you, Flash?
你为什么这么恨我
Why do you hate me so much?
并不是一直是这样的
I didn't always.
以前我对你很痴迷
I was obsessed with you.
长久以来  我一直想成为闪电侠
For so long, I wanted to be the Flash.
我花了几年研究出你是如何变成闪电侠的
I spent years figuring out how you came to be.
我复制了那个反应  而且成功了
Duplicated the reaction... and it worked.
我变得跟你一样
I became like you.
那后来发生了什么
Right, so what happened?
穿越时空的能力向我揭示了一个真相
This ability to travel through time revealed a truth.
我注定要成为你最大的敌人
My fate was to become your greatest enemy.
我永远不可能成为闪电侠
I was never going to be the Flash,
所以我成为了你的一切的反面
so I became the reverse of everything that you were.
你救的人越多  受到的喜爱越多
The more people you saved, the more you were loved,
我就要从你身边夺走越多
the more I had to take from you.
所以你杀了我的母亲
That is why you killed my mother?
所以你毁了我的生活
That's why you ruined my life?
就因为你无法成为我吗
Because you couldn't be me?
我变得比你更强大
I became better than you!
我是你唯一无法阻止的人  闪电侠
I am the one thing you cannot stop, Flash!
不  不是的
No, no, no.
再也不是了
Not anymore.
我们的比赛结束了
Our race is over.
你输了
And you lost.
我已经知道你来自哪个时间段了  闪电侠
I've learned what time period you're from, Flash.
早晚有一天  我会知道你的名字
And one day soon, I'll learn your name.
我们需要你马上到表层来
We need you in the Cortex now!
出什么事了
What's happening?
有大量无法控制的电能正在冲击他的大脑
He's experiencing an uncontrollable amount of electrical energy in his brain,
这让他陷入了长时间的癫痫状态
putting him in a prolonged state of chronic seizure.
什么  你能把电能停下来吗
What? Can you stop it?
我不知道
I don't know.
按住他
Hold him down!
我们在努力
We're trying!
-给他打镇定剂  斯诺  快  -快啊
- Sedate him, Snow, now! - Come on! Come on!
苯二氮[镇定剂]  这个应该管用
Benzodiazepine. This should do it.
总算停了
Finally.
-怎么回事  -这是怎么回事
- What? - What was that?
什么情况  我这是怎么了
What's going on? Where the hell am I?
-西斯科  -是时间线
- Cisco! - It's the time line.
什么  你在说什么
What? What are you talking about?
当你...当你抓捕逆闪时
When you--when you captured Reverse-Flash,
我们破坏了时间线
we ruptured the time line.
所以才会有出血和癫痫现象
That's what this-- all the blood and the seizures
还有其他之类的...
and that and all--
西斯科被...时间线的改变影响了
Cisco is being affected to--to-- by the changes to the time line.
过去的改变或者现在的改变
The changes to the past or the changes to the present--
造成了他现在这样
this is what this is.
我们得做点什么
We need to do something.
-我们必须尽快  -做什么
- We need to do it fast. - Like what?
我们必须修复时间线
We need to restore the time line.
巴里  你必须去找逆闪
Barry, you need to get Reverse-Flash
然后尽快把他送回未来去
and send him back to the future as quickly as possible.
-什么  你...  -巴里...
- What? Are you-- - Barry...
我刚抓到他  你就让我送他回去吗
I just caught him! You want me to let him go?
把他留在这里会害死西斯科的
Keeping him here is killing Cisco!
巴里  如果这是救他的唯一办法
Barry, if this is the only way we can save him,
那你就必须这么做
you got to do it!
-你必须放走斯旺  -我办不到
- You got to let go of Thawne! - I can't.
好吧  听我说
Okay, all right, look.
我毁掉了高速机的超光速粒子硬盘
I destroyed the tachyon drive in the speed machine.
我没可能达到送他回家所需要的速度了
There's no way it'll reach a speed necessary to send him back home.
-你可以的  -什么
- You can. - What?
你的速度加上斯旺的速度
Your speed coupled with Thawne's speed,
那就足够把他扔到时间线上了
that'll be enough to catapult him through the time continuum.
你能做到的
You can do it.
好吧  好吧  我们行动吧  动手吧
All right. All right. Let's do it. Let's do it.
该送你回家了
Time to send you home.
时间悖论  是啊
The time paradox. Yeah.
你们都干涉了自己根本不了解的事物
You've all messed with something you don't understand.
能不能帮个忙  把嘴闭上
Can you do me a favor and just shut up?
你到底要如何送我回家呢
And how exactly are you going to send me home?
你不用操心
Don't worry about it.
你修好了麦吉博士的超光速粒子设备吗
You fixed Dr. Mcgee's tachyon device?
不  我想出了另一个方法
No, I came up with a different method.
是吗
Is that so?
你到底是谁
Who are you?
一个无关紧要的人
No one of consequence.
不
No.
我表示怀疑
I doubt that.
我又赢了  闪电侠
I win again, Flash.
你需要做的就是为他提供足够的动量
All you have to do is provide him with enough momentum
让他突破时空的壁障
to get him past the space-time barrier.
-知道了  -听我说
- All right. - Hey, listen to me.
斯旺知道了你
Thawne knows about you.
就在此地  此时
Right here, right now.
他就是在这里认识你们所有人的
This is where he learns about you, all of you.
他就是这样得知了尖端科研实验室
It's how he knows about S.T.A.R. Labs,
得知了我的存在...
how he knows about me--
这个地球上的哈里森·威尔斯
The Harrison Wells from this earth.
我无能为力
And there's nothing I can do about it.
你也做不了什么
There's nothing you can do about it.
他原来的故事就是这样的
This is his origin story,
不管你怎么做都会发生
and it's going to happen no matter what you do.
但现在  就在这
But right here, right now...
你可以把他送回他的时代
you can send him back to his time.
你可以拯救你的朋友
You can save your friend.
你可以拯救西斯科  然后继续你的生活
You can save Cisco and then move on with your life.
这可能会是件好事
This could be a good thing.
你终于能放手了
You can finally let go of him.
我可以把他扔到三世纪以前
I could throw him three centuries from now.
但我会一直记着他的
He'll always be a part of me.
是时候把你送回你的归宿了
Time to send you back where you belong.
我们很快会再见  闪电侠
We'll meet again soon, flash.
我知道
I know.
随时恭候
And every time, I'll be ready for you.
快
Hurry.
他成功了
He did it.
他会没事的
He's gonna be okay.
我不明白我们到这来干嘛
I don't understand what we're doing here.
和你一样  我以为
Well, just like you, I thought that
假如能在这个地球上找到我的二重身的话
if I could find my doppelganger on this Earth,
我可以用他的健康细胞
I could replace my damaged cells
替换我的受损细胞
with some of his healthy ones.
相信我  当我无法在这个星球上
And believe me, I was just as shocked as you
找到另一个杰伊·加里克时
when I couldn't find
我跟你一样惊讶
a Jay Garrick anywhere on this planet.
我花了好一阵才弄明白
Took me a while to figure it out...
但最终我找到了他
But eventually I found him.
他叫亨特·佐勒蒙
His name is Hunter Zolomon.
亨特·佐勒蒙
Hunter Zolomon?
为什么他的名字跟你不一样
Why doesn't he have the same name as you?
就我知道的信息来看
From what I could gather,
他妈妈死于难产
his mother died during childbirth.
他从一个领养家庭换到另一个
He bounced around from family to family,
但最终被佐勒蒙夫妇收养
but eventually was adopted and raised by the Zolomons.
但这跟他不能帮你有什么关系
But why does that mean he can't help you?
我变成极速者时  DNA发生了突变
My DNA was mutated when I became a speedster.
只有一个办法能阻止我身上正在发生的事
There's only one way to reverse what's happening to me.
如果我们能抓住极速  我就能重获速度
If we can catch zoom, I can get my speed back.
那我们就去找出抓住极速的最好办法
Then let's finally figure out the best way to do that.
沃利  你好
Wally, hi.
你要进来吗
Um, do you want to come in?
不  我不耽搁了  我只是...
No, I-I can't stay. I just--
我想告诉你  我准备接受你的建议
I wanted to tell you that I'm gonna take your advice
去看我妈妈
and go see my mom.
好
Okay.
爱瑞丝  我...我想知道
Iris, I was-- I was wondering
你愿不愿意跟我一起去
if you would come with me.
好  好啊  我很乐意跟你一起去
Yeah, yeah, I would-- I would love that.
-好啊  -好
- Yeah? - Okay.
我的头就像被老虎钳夹住了一样
My head feels like it's in a vise.
发生什么事了
What happened?
我想是你一次震了太多次元
I think you vibed one too many dimensions.
或许我不该再这么做了
Maybe I should stop doing that.
是啊  他会没事的
Yeah, he's gonna be fine.
你们是怎么...让震波停下来的
How did you, um... get the vibing to stop?
我们把斯旺送回他的时间段了
We sent Thawne back to his time.
你放走了他
You let him go?
我不能让他再伤害一个我关心的人
I couldn't let him take another person I cared about.
-谢谢  -没事
- Thank you. - Of course.
我需要一个大贝利汉堡
Okay, I think I need a Big Belly Burger.
-还有谁要吗  -我不用  谢谢
- Anyone? - I'm good, thank you.
我来一个  不加酱菜
Yeah, no pickles.
两个三层三层堡
Two triple triples, please.
你有钱吗
You got money?
好好休息  我就在外面
Rest up, all right? I'll be out here.
帕蒂在去米德韦城的火车上了
So, Patty--she's on a train to Midway City right now, huh?
米德韦城是DC宇宙中鹰侠和鹰女的城市
我也必须得放手让她走
I had to let her go too.
我在想你说过的话
I was thinking about what you said,
当闪电侠  一部分是你有能力做到
that part of being the flash is that you have the ability
别人做不到的酷炫事情
to do amazing things that nobody else can do.
现在我们知道一百年后
And we see now that a hundred years from now,
你还会继续这么做
you'll still be doing them.
但另一部分是
But the other part is,
你会不断牺牲
you're gonna be loaded with sacrifices,
你要做艰难的抉择
and you're gonna have hard choices to make,
将会有很多事情  最终让你
and there's gonna be a lot of things where eventually
不得不放手
you'll have to let 'em go.
你得为此做好准备
You got to be ready for that.
是的  我准备好了
I am. I'm ready.
真是我的好孩子
That's my boy.
太奇怪了
That's weird.
巴里  我在火车上
Barry, I'm on the train.
有个男的拿着枪
There's a--there's a man with a gun.
好  你等等  我去找人帮忙
All right, hold on. I-I-I'll get you help.
大家都没事吧
Is everyone okay?
巴里·艾伦
大家都没事
Everyone's fine.
那是假警报  但
It was a false alarm, but...
还是谢谢你这么快赶来  闪电侠
thanks for coming so fast, flash.
在我离开前  我想确保一切都正常
Just want to make sure everything's okay before I go.
别担心
Don't worry.
一切都好
Everything's good.
再见  巴里
Good bye, Barry.